<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Han Kyung Sung&apos;s blog</title>
    <description>Han Kyung Sung&apos;s blog</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>2021-06-03</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 05:02:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Database Index</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;database-index-postgresql&quot;&gt;Database Index (PostgreSQL)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered this today at work. A few weeks ago, we have a problem with selecting rows in one of the tables we use in the database was super slow that causes an issue. The table contained about 5 million rows this selecting rows process shouldn’t take that long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My colleague brought a good idea that we can create an index for the column we used to select in the table. Our team agreed to use that method and it worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kinda knew what is database index cons and pros from class in University but never had a chance to experience it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I had to delete 8 rows from a table that has about 6000 rows and it took about 7 seconds to delete the rows! This is one of the cons of indexing a database. When you indexing the database, you can select it faster but insert/update/delete operations will be slow! and that table had 3 indexes created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is amazing to see something you learned from the paper and see it in the field. Now, I know that this will gives me a good memory to memorize this longer. Thank you, my co-workers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2021-06-03</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2021-06/database-index</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2021-06/database-index</guid>
        
        <category>TIL</category>
        
        <category>database</category>
        
        
        <category>Daily</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello First Post</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-my-first-post&quot;&gt;Hello My First Post.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello, my blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This my first website ever had and I believe that this would change my lifestyle. 
There are two points I started this blog.
First, I wanted to show and prove what I have done.
Second, I wanted to record what I learn in everyday life. It doesn’t have to be related to my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/renyuanz/leonids/tree/leonids-jekyll&quot;&gt;Leonids&lt;/a&gt; theme to start my first blog ever. 
I am shocked that Jekyll and the theme make the static website simple and handy. I think the best part of it is using a Markdown file to make a post.
Eventually, I want to make my website using my current knowledge and the tech stack I use, but this Github pages blog will be my first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the blog begin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2021-06-03</pubDate>
        <link>/articles/2021-05/the-first-post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/articles/2021-05/the-first-post</guid>
        
        <category>Daily</category>
        
        
        <category>Daily</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
